JIM BUITT

Park Ridge, IL 60068 914.356.0043

jbuitt@gmail.com jim.buitt.com

SUMMARY

Senior DevOps Engineer: extensive Linux system administration experience with expertise in programming, provisioning, and maintaining AWS cloud infrastructure, network components, and configuration management tools. Process improvement mindset through the development of efficient and effective software deployment and automation strategies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Shell Scripting • Python • Perl • Regular Expressions • PHP • SQL

Development Tools: Git • Vagrant • VS Code • Sonarqube • phpunit • GNU make

Web Coding: HTML5 • jQuery • Laravel • Boostrap • NodeJS • JSON & YAML •

RESTful APIs

Operating Systems: Ubuntu • Debian • Amazon Linux 2 • RHEL & CentOS • macOS •

Windows

SSL/TLS certificates • VPNs • Firewalls • Snort IDS • JSON Web

Tokens • OWASP Top 10 • GnuPG

Databases: MySQL • PostgreSQL • RDS Aurora • MongoDB • SQLite •

OpenLDAP

Caches & CDNs: Redis • Memcached • CloudFront • CloudFlare • MaxCDN

Storage: ZFS • Linux Volume Manager • iSCSI • RAID • NetApp • Synology •

GlusterFS

Elastic Beanstalk • EC2 • S3 • Lambda • RDS • API Gateway • **AWS Services**:

Cognito • VPC • CloudFront • IAM • SNS • SQS • WAF • ECR

CI/CD Tools: AWS CodeBuild & CodePipeline • GitLab CI • Jenkins • Bitrise

Configuration Management: Ansible, AWX/Tower, & Semaphore • CloudFormation • Puppet

JIRA & Confluence • GitHub • Bitrise • Trello • Qualys CloudView •

Cloud SaaS Services: Microsoft AppCenter • Miro

Virtualization: VMWare • Proxmox • KVM • Virtualbox

Containerization: Docker • Docker Compose • Portainer • Kubernetes • LXC • ECR

Monitoring Tools: New Relic • Nagios • CloudWatch • CloudTrail • Sensu • Grafana

Application Logging: Graylog • ELK Stack • Splunk • CloudWatch Logs

Networking: TCP/IP • Ethernet • DNS • DHCP • SSH • NFS • Wi-Fi

Open-Source Tools: Apache • Nginx • curl • Wireshark • nmap • Firefox • tmux

Data Structures & Algorithms • Application Architecture • High

Technology Concepts:

Availability • RESTful APIs • Software Development Lifecycle

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ASSURANT, CHICAGO, IL

2019 - Present

Senior DevOps Engineer

- Lead Senior DevOps Engineer, for the Emerging Channels team, responsible for the B2B & B2C cloud infrastructure
- Provision & manage original and all new AWS infrastructure for company B2B and B2C mobile insurance applications
- Write and maintain CloudFormation templates for creating and managing AWS infrastructure
- Create & manage CI/CD process for developers and Code Pipelines in AWS to assist developer team in deploying code to DEV, QA, UAT, and PROD environments
- Utilize Bitrise to build iOS and Android apps & release to Apple and Google Play stores for PROD releases
- Set up and monitor B2B and B2C applications using Nagios, New Relic, and CloudWatch and provided 24x7 DevOps support for applications; set up SOPs for the triage of PROD alerts
- Perform ongoing security audits of AWS infrastructure using Qualys CloudView with immediate issue mitigation and/or resolution
- Write and securely deploy Ansible playbooks to propagate application changes to servers
- Document and maintain all SOPs, HOWTOs, and release notes in Confluence

PUNCHKICK INTERACTIVE, CHICAGO, IL

2013 - 2019

Senior Linux System Administrator

- Lead Systems Administrator, IT Manager, office Safety Warden, and Help Desk support for the organization.
- Developed architecture, built out, maintained, and scaled application infrastructure for client projects
- Developed hosting agreements and service-level agreements for client hosting
- Installed and maintained operating system applications, security, and patches for 150+ company and client servers
- Provisioned, configured, and maintained physical hardware & virtual servers for the internal network infrastructure and CI/CD
- Proactively maintained system integrity supporting change management, disaster recovery, and problem management
- Implemented and managed system backups, storage management, performance/tuning and capacity planning using customwritten software
- Created shell and Perl scripts, and use Ansible to automate system administration tasks
- Created LEMP-based websites and RESTful APIs to assist in administration of local tools & procedures for managing employee accounts, server inventory, server backups, and server/application monitoring
- Set-up/administered MDM for all company laptops (Apple) using Meraki Device Manager w/ Apple DEP & VPP
- Automated employee onboarding and offboarding procedures, including integration with Snipe-IT inventory system.

YESHIVA UNIVERSITY, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SERVICES, New York, NY

2010 - 2013

Linux System Administrator

- Lead Linux Systems Administrator for SunGard Banner (160 servers)
- Planned, installed, maintained, and troubleshooted HP, NetApp, and ESX software and hardware
- Backup Engineer responsible for backup monitoring, troubleshooting, storage management, performance/tuning and capacity planning using Symantec NetBackup
- Evaluated, installed and configured support tools and third-party application software
- Wrote shell and Perl scripts to automate system administration tasks

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

AMAZON CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

Expected August 2022

Southern Illinois University at Carbondale - Carbondale, IL

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

1999